Let's say Taiwan wanted to create a
reserve tomorrow.
How will you hold Bitcoin? Are there
custodians and are they scaled up? Are
they audited? Are they secure?
What exactly is the mechanism to hold
it? Actually, I think Taiwan was on the
receiving end of that, too. I think
Trump said Yasha Baghavan
you got to pay for the protection. So,
things can change very quickly in the
world. We've seen that with Venezuela
and now Iran. Things happen now.
And in a world where things are
changing, relationships are changing,
the counterparty risk is changing, you
need to have an asset without
counterparty risk, and that is Bitcoin.
>> You predicted that Bitcoin will hit $1
million
by the end of 2025.
>> My new prediction is 1.33 million by the
end of 2026.
>> Because?
>> Do you want to buy Bitcoin in 2030 for a
million dollars or do you want to buy it
in 2026 for 68,000? [music]
>> Every model says it's going to go to a
million dollars. Why aren't people just
buying Bitcoin at a discount now?
>> This is an unprecedented time where you
have a down market or bear market and
you have a massive accumulator that's
going full speed ahead with buying
Bitcoin and he's not stopping. So, if
you go back to my 2024 prediction of why
I thought Bitcoin was going to hit a
million, it was because
Bitcoin is 4 5.5 times more scarce than
silver and I think Bitcoin has the
potential to at least do a
5x because it's more scarce, but 10x is
not out of the question and that puts us
to a million.
>> Bitcoin and gold has kind of like
[music] lost its correlation. People are
asking if the digital gold narrative is
still alive.
>> We're moving into a world that is more
uncertain. Can you keep dollars forever
and trade with dollars forever? It's a
question mark.
>> How does the transition [music] going to
happen? How does that work?
>> Nobody knows, but it's going to be
sudden. So, I think how it plays out is
Bitcoin starts to go parabolic. You
know, it goes up to
200,000
>> [music]
>> and then people start to FOMO in because
suddenly there's easy to get. Then it
goes up to 500.
>> Mhm.
>> And then you see countries starting to
get into it. And then that thing goes up
to a million.
And I think there will be a time where
the fiat pricing of things doesn't
match. So, you will be able to buy a
house for
I don't know, 100,000 satoshis or
something like that.
>> Tell us about gold candle and omega
candle.
>> A gold candle is a 10K candle on the
daily. It's actually happened. We've had
10K days in the past. Omega candle is
100K candle in one day. It's only a
matter of time before you see Bitcoin go
up 100,000 in a day. And
it could be from
150 to 200,000.
Or could be from
200,000 [music] to
500,000 in 3 days.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Joining me today is Samson Mow. He is
the CEO of Gen 3. One of our most
popular guest. He works on Bitcoin
adoption worldwide. And just really
encouraging nations to adopt Bitcoin
strategy. Welcome to Taipei.
>> Thanks, Bonnie. Great to be back.
>> What's in Taipei? What's new? What
brought you back?
>> Lots of things. I think Taiwan is one of
the interesting places in the world that
could potentially adopt Bitcoin
relatively quickly. And there is
definitely a need for Bitcoin and at the
strategic and national level here.
And we work closely with JC Ko. He's a
friend of mine and we're trying to move
things forward in the legislature.
>> You said
Taiwan has this unique characteristics.
What is it?
>> Well, I think Taiwan is very
forward-thinking in general.
and
>> is more agile in general than other
countries, many other countries.
And there's a close proximity to the US,
much like Japan.
And I think given everything that's
happened in the US,
I believe the lawmakers and the
government in Taiwan should be looking
closely at that to learn from it and
possibly emulate. So, creating a
strategic reserve and
pushing forward-thinking policy, de
minimis tax exemptions, encouraging, you
know, people and businesses to adopt
Bitcoin, and opening up the market to
Bitcoin ETFs,
companies like strategy, that kind of
corporate structure for Bitcoin
accumulation.
And also at a national level, it's
important for national defense
for, you know, many, many reasons. And
we can talk more about that, but
everything
says Taiwan should adopt Bitcoin.
>> Talking about nation adopting Bitcoin,
last time you were here, it was 2024,
and we're talking about US and the
strategic Bitcoin reserve. It happened,
but the price didn't really move.
>> Well, they didn't buy. So, the strategic
reserve, you know, it's it has mixed
reviews in the Bitcoin
ecosystem and community. Some people
think it's a nothingburger. Like, yeah,
they just did it to placate people and
make us all happy.
But it actually did create the reserve
and
technically, government agencies cannot
sell their Bitcoin now.
And even more importantly, they
separated the crypto into a
crypto stockpile, which can be sold
to buy Bitcoin. And overall, the entire
structure allows for budget-neutral
Bitcoin accumulation, too.
While they haven't done anything, at
least they're not selling, and the
government agencies can't rogue sell
Bitcoin rogue like go rogue and sell
Bitcoin. Like, you know, in in Germany,
one of the states sold all of their
Bitcoin.
Uh but, at least there is this kind of
structure in place that paves the way
for more Bitcoin adoption.
And it is good legislature. I think in
Taiwan, they're looking to do something
similar in other places, too. But, it's
just kind of setting the tone of
what the government should be doing,
which is holding the Bitcoin.
And then you have other avenues, like
the Bitcoin Act. Uh Cynthia Lummis
tabled that to accumulate 1 million
Bitcoin. And that's not budget neutral.
So, I think even though nothing has
really happened, it is still leaps and
bounds ahead of many other countries,
especially given the fact that the US is
in many ways a Bitcoin superpower, if
you look at it.
The bulk of ETFs are in the US.
The bulk of custodians of Bitcoin are in
the US.
The bulk of corporate treasury holdings
of Bitcoin is in the US.
And I think the US is still the largest
holder of Bitcoin. Maybe China, maybe
the US.
Just from seized uh
proceeds of crime and whatnot. So, the
US is really a Bitcoin superpower, even
if they did nothing else. But, they're
actively working on legislation and new
ways to adopt Bitcoin at a bigger scale.
>> Are they really?
>> I think so. At least
it is one of the countries where they're
trying to do things, right? So, they
passed the the GENIUS Act.
The CLARITY Act is, you know, in various
states of discussion right now,
being blocked by Coinbase.
But, uh overall, the US is open for
business. And I think it's far more
advanced, and they have the
infrastructure in place
for when they need to adopt at a
national level. This is why
for us at Jan3, it's
when we go to approach governments, we
kind of say,
"You have a lot to do to catch up,
right? So, let's say Taiwan wanted to
create a reserve tomorrow."
>> Mhm.
>> "How will you hold the Bitcoin? Are
there custodians and are they scaled up?
Are they audited? Are they secure?
You know, what exactly is the mechanism
to hold it? I I don't even think that um
Taiwan public companies can really hold
Bitcoin easily right now without some
workarounds. So, there's a lot of steps
to go through before you can open the
floodgates to a large accumulation.
>> So, when you advise these
people in the government, lawmakers, do
you lay out the step-by-steps?
>> We generally give a broad outline like
you should have a national system for
custodians in the country. I think Japan
is starting to have that now.
Uh I think they have one at Crypto
Garage and um
at a nation level, I'm not sure you
would want to use custodian. You could.
>> Mhm.
>> But, I think it'd be better have some,
you know, cold storage system
for the government separately from the
is not a normal
corporate custodian.
And that does not exist yet.
>> Should people be allowed to check the
balance and
>> I think so.
>> Really?
>> Yeah.
>> Huh.
>> It's just like the question of how much
gold is in Fort Knox right now. When the
Trump administration came into power,
one of the things that was promised was
an audit of Fort Knox.
>> Mhm.
>> And that hasn't happened. We don't know
if there is even gold in Fort Knox. But,
I think as a country, you want to show
here's my address, here's the Bitcoin
that we hold. And the public can verify
cuz those are public funds, right? It's
kind of
it makes sense to do that.
>> I think people are interested in the
game theory because there is this FOMO
element in it. So, once you know, the
argument was once US started buying,
well, they're not buying yet, but once
US started this plan, other countries
will be like, you know what, we can't
miss out. Everyone's going to start
doing it. But are they really doing it?
>> No one's really doing it yet, but
all the
all the dominoes are sort of lining up.
So, you even have central banks now that
are buying like the the Czech Central
Bank, I think has bought um another
uh
Eastern European Central Bank has
bought. I can't remember the name right
now, but they
are starting to accumulate Bitcoin at a
nation level, if not in a strategic
reserve or something.
>> But I guess the main question for these
countries are, why do we need to hold
Bitcoin?
>> That's a good question, and I think
people will figure out again. The
problem is
a lot of people misunderstand how money
works. So, Bitcoin is viewed as a risk
asset or a tech stock. That's why we
track. So, when when all the software
companies were crashing because AI was
going to replace every software company,
you know, Bitcoin came down with it.
Very weird correlation, but people think
Bitcoin is just a piece of software, but
Bitcoin is actually a transformation of
money. It's closer to gold, but it's
better than gold because you can
teleport it and memorize it. So, it
changes the entire paradigm.
The way the world works right now is
counterparty risk is everywhere.
So, for people that don't know,
counterparty risk means you have to rely
on another party to transfer something.
In terms of gold, you can have gold as a
bearer asset with no counterparty risk
because you can have a physical gold
coin.
But that is not scalable.
At a nation-state level, you have you
know, Taiwan has 424 tons of gold.
You can't just take that with you
easily, and a lot of countries store
gold elsewhere like um
Venezuela kept their gold with the Bank
of England.
And then famously the Bank of England
said you can't have it back when they
said we want our gold back, right? And
even I think many European countries,
Germany included, store gold with the
US.
So there's
counterparty risk with gold, which is
before Bitcoin the hardest asset we had.
And then you have the traditional
financial system and if you look at uh
what happened to Russia, they were
effectively debanked as a country and
kicked off of Swift and assets were
frozen and uh treasuries were frozen,
too. They owned a bunch of US
treasuries.
And now
as a country you have to ask yourself
you know, isn't is that an acceptable
risk? Taiwan also has treasuries, too.
And if you remember I think it was last
year
uh many countries suddenly were no
longer
friends with the US, even Canada, where
I'm from. We were suddenly,
you know, persona non grata and you
know, we're talking about uh
annexing Canada as the 51st state. There
was talk about grabbing Greenland and
other things, too. So
I think people have grown up in a world
that has been largely stable
and largely very amicable and largely
very friendly.
Actually, I think Taiwan was on the
receiving end of that, too. I think
Trump said uh you have to pay,
you know, you have to pay for the
protection.
>> Yeah.
>> So things can change very quickly in the
world and we've seen that with Venezuela
and now Iran. Things happen now.
And in a world where things are
changing, relationships are changing
the counterparty risk is changing, you
need to have an asset without
counterparty risk and that is Bitcoin.
And eventually people will come to that
same conclusion, but it's difficult
because Bitcoin is so revolutionary that
people can't really wrap their heads
around it because if they did
they would be buying Bitcoin, they'd be
listening to podcasts and hanging on to
Michael Saylor's every single word, but
they're not. So, this is the current
state of the world we're in. People
don't understand it yet, but they will
because money is a necessity in a
conflict. Let's say you want to defend
your borders from an aggressor. You want
to buy oil.
If you Let's say you wanted to buy oil
from Russia.
Do they want to NTD?
>> Not anymore.
>> Probably not.
Are you going to give them US dollars?
How are you going to give them US
dollars? And where are they going to
keep the US dollars? Cuz US dollars they
don't really
you know, they don't really really exist
at scale outside of the US financial
system, right?
Maybe a stable coin, but those are
centralized and can be frozen, too. So,
let's say in a conflict
you have no more allies that want NTD or
USD. You need a neutral currency that
you can pay and get oil or drones or
aircraft or anti-aircraft missiles,
right? You need to have a money that you
can spend freely and anywhere in the
world to anybody.
>> I think people fail to understand what
Bitcoin really is and they're looking at
the fiat price. Um
something really interesting that I I
observe.
Our last interview was about 2 years ago
>> Yeah.
>> and I still have people commenting under
that video today asking me to have you
back
>> Okay.
>> because they're like, "What happened to
his price prediction?"
>> Yeah.
>> You predicted that Bitcoin will hit $1
million
by the end of 2025.
>> Mhm. My new prediction is 1.33 million
by end of 2026.
>> Because?
>> It's overdue.
>> Mhm.
>> So,
the thing is people get angry when I
make predictions.
Like, how come you're wrong? Like,
>> [laughter]
>> you know, if I was right with
prediction, then I would be a
trillionaire. I'd be richer than Elon
Musk.
But the thing is, it's a prediction and
it is for fun and is also to outline an
interesting phenomenon, which is I'm
going to be right eventually. If you
look at every single price prediction
model, stock-to-flow, power law, we have
one at Jan3, we call it Omega 60.
Um Saylor has a model called Bitcoin 24.
They all converge in the area of 2030,
2031, maybe 2032 of Bitcoin hitting a
million. Mhm. So, every single model
says that. And
the world is largely asleep at the wheel
still. They don't understand what's
happening. They don't understand the
scarcity of Bitcoin. They don't
understand what Bitcoin is. But let's
say they did and let's say the models
are right. Wouldn't you want to front
run that? Like
rationally, do you want to buy Bitcoin
in 2030 for a million dollars or do you
want to buy it in 2026 for $68,000?
>> Mhm.
Mhm.
>> But I think I think what is hard for
people to understand is well, every
model says it's going to go to a million
dollars. Now, why aren't people just
buying Bitcoin at a discount now?
Institutions know or
I I I get it. Retail investors, they
only have I don't know 100k, a million
dollars sitting at the bank. They kind
of have to like be smart about it. But
what about the really wealthy people?
>> They are.
Look at Saylor.
>> Mhm.
>> Right? He's hitting the ATM. He's uh
monetizing STRC,
their their stretch product.
And they're buying non-stop. This is an
unprecedented time where you have a down
market or bear market. And
you have a massive accumulator that's
going full speed ahead with buying
Bitcoin. And he's not stopping, right?
This has never happened in the past
before. So, if you go back to my 2024
prediction of why I thought Bitcoin was
going to hit a million, it was because
of the ETFs. Every other bull run in
Bitcoin history has always been
disrupted or muted because exchanges
were overwhelmed. I used to run an
exchange, too. When the price goes
parabolic and people are suddenly
interested in Bitcoin,
you cannot onboard and KYC people fast
enough.
But the ETFs remove that. And it also
removed the barrier to institutional
adoption.
So, that was why I thought we would hit
1 million very quickly. Now, that didn't
happen, but
it is very, very positive and it is
playing out to hit a million. So, if you
look at the BlackRock ETF, IBIT,
it is their most successful ETF product
to date on a number of metrics,
profitability, revenue generation,
speed to grow to 50-something
billion dollars, right? The rate and
scale of institutional adoption piling
in,
it's just it should have sent Bitcoin
flying upwards, but it hasn't. And I
think Yeah, people are always wondering
why it hasn't not gone parabolic. And I
think it's a number of reasons. There's
no one particular reason.
One is
people are short on cash.
They're poor now because of inflation
and everything.
You know, it's not widely accepted that
inflation is double-digits, but I think
real inflation is somewhere in
double-digits, if not, you know,
you know, 20%.
>> [laughter]
>> If you depends on what you're looking
at, but the other reason is also
uncertainty, like all the conflict
happening.
And the last one is it's just um
people are investing in other things,
like AI and whatnot. So, they're they're
taking capital that would have gone into
Bitcoin and investing in Nvidia or other
things like that. So, Oh, sorry, there's
a fourth one, which is probably more on
the Bitcoin  crypto side, which
is the people that believe in the
four-year cycle.
They think 2025 was the peak.
And now it's just down.
And of course, they're they're selling
because that's what they anticipate.
So, there's like all these little
factors that are playing into price
suppression, but definitely there's a
lot of factors that are
keeping Bitcoin down.
But the thing you have to understand is
there's not an unlimited supply of
Bitcoin.
If you look at stock-to-flow as a
metric,
Bitcoin is five times or 5.5 times more
scarce than silver. And I think Bitcoin
has the potential to at least do a
a 5x because it's more scarce, but 10x
is not out of the question and that
would put us to, you know, a million.
Yeah, like Bitcoin has taken a beating
for the last 6-7 months, right? It's
been 6-7 months of down.
But I think it's it'll reverse and
usually when it reverses, it'll just
reverse violently to the upside because
of the supply shock, but we've never had
a market like this. Like people,
specifically crypto traders like to say,
well, it's so really dumb, but they say
it's going to repeat the past and we're
going to have 80% drawdown.
Not really. I think we've hit the bottom
and
strategy buying, people like to say, oh,
doesn't do anything to the market. He's
buying and it's not even moving it, but
what it is is setting a floor. Like he
is buying aggressively at the bottoms
and
you also have um
basically it's packaging the strategy to
now. So, you can't really short strategy
below 1M NAV. It's kind of dangerous to
do that. I think people realize it. So,
there's kind of like a double bottom.
There's a Bitcoin bottom and then
there's a strategy bottom simply because
of size of strategy.
So, I think both things will factor into
Bitcoin
having a supply shock where there's just
no more coins and you have more big
treasury companies that will be buying
soon like Adam Back. I think you had him
on.
Uh BSTR is likely going to
de-SPAC in the next 4 weeks, maybe 6
weeks.
And they have 1.5 billion dollars of
capital to deploy in the Bitcoin.
And at uh
68, 67,000,
you know, he's getting close to
$10,000 below Saylor's average price,
which is now 75,000 because he's been
averaging down.
So, I think it's just too good to be
true that Adam is going to de-SPAC
and buy 1.5 billion dollars of Bitcoin
for 10k cheaper than Saylor.
Cuz that has repercussions for the next
10 years, right? That means
BSTR will be averaging you know,
their average cost will stay lower and
they'll be averaging up more gradually,
whereas if Bitcoin recovers to um 80k,
Saylor's averaging up again, not down.
>> Now I'm wondering if it's safe to
preach people or tell people it is
always a good idea to buy Bitcoin at any
price.
>> It is always a good
thing to buy Bitcoin at any price.
>> Explain to me why.
>> Well,
if you just ignore all the financial
engineering with strategy and everything
like that, you know,
you can't really time the market and say
Bitcoin is going to go up or down. You
don't know.
>> Right.
>> So you always want to be deploying into
the market because you know for a fact
that in 10 years,
Bitcoin will be much higher than it is
now.
Because if it is the scarce asset and it
is replacing gold.
So you you just have to be in the
market. Like there's a saying, time in
the market is more important than timing
the market, you know? And even if you
don't believe that,
Bitcoin is good,
then you should just put your money in
STRC and let Saylor buy the Bitcoin and
he'll keep the 20 to 50% upside and
he'll give you 11%.
>> For people that are not familiar with
that product, can you briefly explain
what it is?
>> Yeah, so STRC is uh
it's basically a fixed income product.
Um it's basically Saylor stripping out
the volatility of Bitcoin. Basically,
he'll pay you 11%. You give him money,
he'll take that and buy Bitcoin. And
when Bitcoin goes up 30%, he gets the
20% gain on it. So it's like a beautiful
kind of arbitrage between those that are
risk-averse or don't understand Bitcoin
and those that understand big because it
is a brilliant instrument. It It's
stripping out the volatility and giving
people a stable income.
And they don't need to buy Bitcoin. And
those that believe and understand
Bitcoin will buy Bitcoin. And in many
ways, this is similar possibly inspired
by the Bitcoin bond that I designed for
El Salvador, which was not on a monthly
scale, but the idea was you buy the
bond, you get a yield, which is covered
by investing half of the bond capital
into mining.
But then after a 5-year period, you
recoup the principal. So, you if you
invest uh
a $100,000 in it, you know that in 10
years, it's a 10-year bond, you get back
your 100,000.
But after the 5-year mark, you get an
increased Bitcoin yield uh on top of the
base coupon.
So, in year 7, 8, 9, maybe your yield is
uh 30, 40, 50%, or 90%, which is pretty
cool, right?
>> What are you working on right now?
>> Lots of stuff.
>> What is the most exciting one?
>> [sighs]
>> I don't want to say yet, but [laughter]
uh
it has to do with
you know, consumer adoption of Bitcoin.
But um
at the nation-state level, we're engaged
with a few countries and on the topic of
a Bitcoin bond.
>> What would it look like?
>> The Bitcoin bond?
>> Yeah.
>> It's like STRC, but instead of monthly,
it's you know,
annual dividend.
>> And it's nation issuing it.
>> It's instead of corporate debt or you
know, a preferred share, it's sovereign
debt.
>> Oh.
>> So, it's at a new level.
>> Is there a point where this
institutional adoption is bad for
Bitcoin?
>> Well, you could say that. And there is
criticism that there's concentration
risk, right? Like Strategy has what?
someone thousand now.
And then BlackRock has 750 something
thousand Bitcoin now. So,
there are people that say say that's
like not great. It's too concentrated.
But BlackRock is buying on behalf of
their clients, right? Just like any
other ETF.
And Saylor,
he has conviction.
>> What is bad about this?
>> Well, the idea is that, you know, what
if uh
what if Saylor decides to sell one day
and dumps it on the market, right? Or
it's just he has outsize influence on
the market because he has so much
Bitcoin, right? And it's one entity.
But there's really no way around it,
right? Like
if Bitcoin is valuable, everyone will
want Bitcoin. And that's what we're
seeing. Countries will want Bitcoin.
Companies will want Bitcoin.
You know, institutions will want
Bitcoin. It's just a natural extension,
just like who wants gold? There's really
nothing you can do except for complain
about it because
it's capitalism. If you want to get it,
go and get it. Nothing is stopping you
from buying more Bitcoin than Saylor. I
think in
a world where Bitcoin is replacing the
entire monetary system, it's going to
absorb gold.
It's going to demonetize all these
precious metals. It's going to absorb
real estate. It's going to absorb a lot
of things.
There
is no limit how big Bitcoin can get. So,
it's everything divided by 21 million,
right?
So,
Yes strategy has a big chunk of it, but
overall, Bitcoin is going to grow from,
1.something trillion
to
100 trillion. And there's enough Bitcoin
for everyone. Even though everyone may
not have one Bitcoin, but you know, one
Bitcoin can be divided up into 100
million satoshis. So, everyone will have
a good number of satoshis.
But that's the nature of wealth. It will
concentrate
somehow.
But the good thing about Bitcoin is
anybody can hold Bitcoin. And Saylor has
even said this, too.
He said uh
not everyone can have Manhattan real
estate, right? But anyone, even some guy
in Africa or Argentina, can buy Bitcoin.
There's nothing stopping them other than
their own
biases or ignorance, but they can buy
Bitcoin just like Sailor can buy
Bitcoin.
>> Earlier we were talking about gold. So,
Bitcoin and gold has kind of like lost
its correlation.
And
people are asking if the digital gold
narrative is still alive.
>> Gold had a run, and I think it was
largely driven by central banks buying
it.
>> Mhm.
>> And
you know, it's normal. Central banks are
centralized. They want central assets
that they control.
Um like China bought a lot of gold.
Uh also some European countries, I think
Poland bought a lot of gold, too. And I
think that largely has that largely
drove the gold rally, right? But that
doesn't really change anything because
gold is still not very portable.
You can have paper gold, or you can have
small amounts of physical gold.
And people don't really understand that
there is a large drop-off
when you have
um when you sell gold. It's easy to buy
it, hard to sell it. You might sell it
at
you know,
generously at 10% discount.
>> Explain that.
>> Because like when people buy it, they
have to verify the gold, right? So,
there's a cost to that. But generally,
gold is meant for selling, not for
buying back, right? You can
I don't know about Taiwan, but in the
US, you can buy gold at Costco.
>> Yeah.
>> You can't sell gold at Costco.
>> True.
>> So,
the distribution chains all exist to
sell gold, not to buy it back. So, a lot
of dealers will give you a haircut.
Like, okay, you want to sell your gold?
What's the market price? You get 10%
lower, 20%, 30%.
And a lot of shipping companies actually
won't take gold because of the risk,
too.
And there are many Bitcoiners that I
know that originated from being gold
bugs. And they learned the hard way.
Like, they had a good chunk of gold and
they wanted to sell it, and they took a
haircut, and it was very hard to sell.
That's not the case with Bitcoin. So,
this is why
gold is not as good as Bitcoin. It's
like defective Bitcoin.
Bitcoin's everything gold wanted to be,
but couldn't be.
But, yeah, gold rallied very hard, and I
think Bitcoin didn't rally. And I think
the time will come when Bitcoin does
rally because, you know, everything has
rallied except for Bitcoin. S&P's
rallied.
Gold, silver has rallied.
Oil has rallied. Bitcoin has not
rallied, and it's overdue for the rally.
>> Do you think Bitcoin is going to replace
the monetary system, or have you updated
your prediction on what would happen in
the world?
>> I think it has to replace the monetary
system.
>> It has to.
>> It has to. Cuz the monetary system is
broken.
Like, the US is now 39 trillion in debt.
I think when we met a couple years back,
it was 34 or 35. But,
um, 39 trillion is astronomical.
And most countries have a large amount
of debt, and they just
there's no way out of it. Like, Japan,
which Japan is another country that
we're very interested in for
nation-state adoption. That's why we
focus our efforts there because it has
the highest debt-to-GDP ratio, right?
Something has to give there, too.
But, Japan is a wholly different beast.
They've been financing the world,
basically, through cheap yen.
And, you know, that seems to be coming
to an end. But, everything in the fiat
system seems to be coming to an end. You
could say it's pessimistic, but I think
it's just
things have to reconcile eventually. You
cannot keep printing money and
increasing the debt forever. And
>> is, it it has been working, and yes,
it's bad, but why can't it just
continue? Yeah, the numbers are huge
already. It can be even even bigger. So,
what to everyday people?
>> I think Japan, the Bank of Japan is now
buying most of their own debt back.
Right? So, you can see the uh
whatever you want to call it, the game
of musical chairs is ending, right?
Nobody wants to buy it, right? People
are moving to hard assets, and that's
why gold rallied.
At least part of the reason why gold
rallied because
you know, you can say it can go on
forever, and theoretically
yeah, it can keep printing forever.
But eventually it loses some meaning.
But more importantly, you're seeing
frac- fractures in the system.
We're moving into a world that is more
uncertain.
Can you keep dollars forever and trade
with dollars forever?
It's a question mark.
>> How does the transition going to happen?
Is it cuz I'm trying to picture, okay,
we're we're using fiat money, and then
all of a sudden people are like, oh,
this is not sustainable,
and let's
you know, add Bitcoin into this picture.
How does that work?
>> Nobody knows, but it's going to be
sudden. So, I think how it plays out is
Bitcoin starts to go parabolic, you
know, it goes up to
200,000, and then people start to FOMO
in because suddenly they're interested
again. Then it goes up to 500.
And then you see countries starting to
get into it because, oh, guess what, we
need Bitcoin now. And then that sends us
up to a million.
And I think there will be a time where
the fiat pricing of things doesn't
match. So, you will be able to buy a
house for
I don't know, 100,000 satoshis or
something like that. It's going to be a
really really weird thing. But
eventually what people will do is
reprice things in satoshis instead of in
fiat currency, right?
Because fiat currency is meaningless.
>> Okay, chart shows this chart, okay,
shows that Google trend
of interest in Bitcoin. 2017 it was at a
that's the peak. 2021 it was at 63.
Uh this cycle's peak 2025 October it was
at at 37. And right now
we're about to head into April of 2026.
We're at 27, 28.
>> Mhm.
>> Pretty terrible.
>> I don't know. I don't think so. I don't
think it matters.
>> Really?
>> Because Bitcoin is not something for the
masses yet. If it was for the masses,
then
we wouldn't be at these levels of price.
>> Yeah.
>> We'd be at millions right now.
And it it's also similar like you have
the fear and greed indicator, right?
>> Yeah.
>> And then you have um
the prediction markets saying Bitcoin is
uh there's a chance Bitcoin's going to
go down.
>> I saw that.
>> But all of these things are sentiment.
>> Mhm.
>> And sentiment you know the normal
distribution, right? There's the
high IQ and the low IQ and the mid
curve.
Sentiment is basically the mid curve.
It's like what
the normal
person thinks, right?
>> that where the money is at? Like that's
the majority of money.
>> No, that's where the debt is. Like if
you look at the normal person, they're
in debt.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay.
>> So
sentiment is the mid curve emission.
It's just like the barometer of the
average person's fear.
And or or interest in Bitcoin or lack of
interest in Bitcoin. It is not the first
principle thinkers, right? Again, you
should look at Warren Buffett. You know,
he's not the mid curve.
He's the opposite. You know, we can say
either he's on this side or that side,
but he's not the mid curve for certain,
right? So he's the one that's greedy
when others are fearful.
>> Well, that was very dangerous. Oh my
god. Talk Tell me more about Warren
Buffett because he does not like
Bitcoin.
>> Well, if Warren Buffett was our age, I
he would like Bitcoin. But there's a
certain point in time in which
you can't understand something that's so
drastically different. You either
dismiss it outright or you cannot grasp
the core concepts behind it. But it I
think if Warren Buffett was our age, he
would be all in on Bitcoin because it is
disruptive and it is it is a powerful
tech. If you look at the boomers, like
they believe strongly in real estate
because that was what they knew growing
up and that's what benefited them. They
bought a house for $1,000 and now it's
worth millions of dollars.
So, they believe in what benefited them
in the past or what was transformative
for them in the past, right? And the
irony is
real estate only boom because it was
a new safe haven after the gold standard
was abandoned,
right?
So,
in a in many ways, if the gold standard
wasn't abandoned, they would all all the
real estate boomers would be gold bugs.
We're in such an interesting phase of
the world where anything can happen,
right? Like
you know, oil can go up here and now
it's back down and it's probably going
to go back up again.
Gold was up here and now it's back down.
Silver was up here and now it's back
down. Bitcoin is here and now it's going
to go up again, right? So, it's just a
massive amount of uncertainty in the
world.
>> Yeah.
>> And I don't think it's going to get more
certain in the next few years, you know,
it definitely things are changing very
rapidly.
But again, going back to the very
beginning of our conversation, Bitcoin
is the only asset with no counterparty
risk
and you have to understand that.
If you don't understand it,
try to understand it cuz it's really
important to understand that.
>> Tell us about gold candle and omega
candle.
>> A gold candle is a 10K candle on the
daily.
Um
and it's actually happened. We've had
10K days in the the
And omega candle is a 100k candle in one
day.
And we haven't had it yet on the US
dollar charts, but we've had it in a few
other places. I think Iran had a omega
candle, Lebanon has it, Egypt has it in
their currencies.
>> [laughter]
>> But
it just goes to show like the world is
very turbulent right now. And it's only
a matter of time before you see Bitcoin
go up 100,000 in a day. And
it could be from
150 to 200,000. Or it could be from
200,000 to
500,000 in 3 days, right? That's the
level of
uh
volatility you should be expecting now.
If you go back and look at the the chart
of
the German mark against gold in World
War
the chart is like this over a 1-year
period up and down.
I think that's what we're seeing now.
We're seeing massive volatility and
the cool thing is the volatility to the
downside is muted because we have
corporations buying as a buyer of last
resort right now.
So the only thing up only thing is up
now, volatility to the upside, which
will shock and awe people. And they'll
show that hey, we were right.
>> Yeah, I I think in one of your
interviews you said we have nowhere to
go but up or something along the line.
>> Well, there is nowhere to go. If you
understand everything, where do you
store your money, right?
You want to buy real estate and get a
Dubai happening where you're stuck,
right?
Real estate is highly illiquid. Even if
you tokenize it, it's still like highly
illiquid cuz the base asset is
physical on the ground, stuck in the
ground.
You could buy gold, but again
it's not that liquid unless it's paper
gold, but then it's paper gold and it's
an IOU. Same for any other metal.
You could buy a stock, but a stock is a
wrapper for a company with management
and with problems and it can be replaced
just as we saw software companies
getting replaced by general AI.
And you could say, well, what about
investing in Nvidia or something like
that or
whatever, but there's always something
new, right? But a permissionless
store of value that is bearer and
immutable cannot be replaced. That is
it. That's the
apex predator of money. Does not get any
better than that.
>> You have a prediction that says in 2026
Elon Musk is going to come back to
Bitcoin.
>> Yeah.
>> What is that about?
>> Well, we know he knows about Bitcoin. We
know that he knows crypto cuz he likes
Dogecoin.
And the what prompted that was his
friends like the All In podcast guys.
They're mostly in California.
And if you remember a few months back,
California was
slated to put through a wealth tax and
everyone was leaving or actually a lot
of people have left California,
billionaires.
And Elon runs in that same circle,
right? So, if they're understanding that
their stuff is targeted, that their
wealth is being targeted, they have to
come to the conclusion that I need
wealth stored in something that cannot
be seized. And that's really Bitcoin.
So, Elon has to understand Bitcoin
eventually.
>> I talked to
people behind D-Cash and yes, okay,
maybe you can correct their narrative.
Why do you think
Bitcoin has privacy if we can see every
transaction on chain?
>> Bitcoin is not private, but it is
pseudonymous. But more what's more
likely is I'll pay you with lightning or
with liquid and then you can't see cuz
those are private. It's a Bitcoin
sidechain and lightning is a layer two
micro payments network and you cannot
see any of that stuff. So, that's false
right out of the bag.
But, let's say
you value privacy, you want to buy
crypto
from an exchange
and you don't want anyone to know about
it.
Guess what? The exchange knows and
they're reporting it to the tax
authority. So, you gained nothing.
>> So, all the problems that people are
trying to solve for Bitcoin.
>> There are no problems that Bitcoin
doesn't solve.
There are manufactured problems that
people say that Bitcoin has.
>> Like what?
>> I don't know. Anything.
Pick any altcoin. Like what Ethereum
says that Bitcoin is not programmable.
Bitcoin is programmable.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, there's nothing much to defend
because it's a false thing, but that's
what they base their entire value
proposition and identity off of.
Something that they say Bitcoin is
deficient in when it's not.
>> So, you don't see a world where there
will be another
thing that is similar
and that has more consensus.
>> No, because you can only create digital
scarcity once. Everything else is a copy
of it.
>> Mhm.
>> Right? Like if you try to make a Bitcoin
today,
you won't be able to launch it
organically like Bitcoin. And then you
don't have the network effects, right?
But, still like
you won't it won't work. It'll be
centralized.
>> Going back to your earlier
um prediction, you said 1.3 million
dollars by this year?
>> Yeah.
>> Why 1.3?
>> Just to increase the number of it.
>> You can't stay the same. It has to go
up.
>> I think we're long overdue for a big
move up.
>> What has to happen for that to happen?
>> Just time.
>> Time.
>> Everyone is accumulating a massive
amount of Bitcoin, right?
Saylor has 760,000.
now, right?
I don't think there's that much Bitcoin
out there that he can keep buying
without the price coming up.
And the structure of STRC lets him buy
without any dilution. So,
it's a very powerful instrument. And
then you have Adam's company BSTR
coming. So, just imagine
four or five companies all doing this.
>> Mhm.
>> It's going to go up. And then BlackRock.
And now Morgan Stanley wants to compete
with compete with BlackRock. Then you
throw a country or two into the mix.
There's just not enough Bitcoin and
you'll have a supply shock.
>> Is there a scenario where it doesn't
happen?
Like
Bitcoin is just stuck at this level and
>> No, because it's scarce, right? Like
I think this is the greatest trick that
the market is playing on people that
there's so much Bitcoin that it's always
going to be low. But that's just not
true.
Bitcoin is so scarce that people can't
fathom how scarce it is. There's only 21
million units of this.
And again, this is like something that
the masses don't understand, the concept
of a finite asset.
They're familiar with assets that are
kind of scarce,
but the total number is unknown. Right?
You don't know how much gold there is.
You don't know how much silver there is.
You have estimates.
You don't know how much oil there is,
but you think oil is scarce, you know.
It's going to run out eventually cuz
there was only so many so many so many
dinosaurs that died.
So, you know, they kind of have a vague
concept of scarcity, but they don't
understand absolute scarcity, which is
what Bitcoin is. And when you hit that
limit, when there is no free float on
the exchanges, when the traders that
are, you know,
using Bitcoin as this kind of uh
free-floating asset to,
you know, market make or provide
liquidity to the market. When that dries
up, then Bitcoin will just run.
>> Why would that dry up? Because if it's
so volatile, then it's an interesting
thing to trade.
>> Because there's only 21 million Bitcoin.
>> But they're trading the derivatives.
They're not
>> I I think there's both.
>> Mhm.
>> Derivatives definitely will dampen or
amplify it. But they need spot Bitcoin.
So that we know there are 2 to 3 million
BTC on exchanges kind of has this free
float.
And that free float will be eroded. It's
just a question of when.
>> So right now there's 1 to 2 million?
>> 2 to 3 million, depending on who you
ask, on exchange.
>> Worldwide?
>> Yeah.
>> That's not a lot.
>> No, it's not a lot.
>> We have 1 million left.
>> To mine.
>> To be Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> And
it's insane.
>> Yeah.
So
reality was is going to reconcile
eventually, and then the price will go
up because of that scarcity.
>> Are you still buying?
>> I don't know. If I had money, sure.
>> [laughter]
>> But you think retail investors should
buy?
>> I think anybody
that wants a future should buy Bitcoin.
>> If you talk about people accumulating as
many Bitcoin as you can, what's the end
game? So let's say, I don't know, I have
enough,
but I still don't feel rich because I
can't really sell it because the the
strategy is don't sell it, right? So I
can't really enjoy my life now.
>> I don't think it's true they should
never sell.
>> [snorts]
>> Like life is finite, time is finite for
people. So you need to
live your life. So this is the purpose
of Bitcoin. It is not that you should
buy it and never sell it. That's like
it's more of a slogan, right? You never
sell your Bitcoin. And strategy can do
that cuz it's a corporation, but at a
individual level,
you know,
it's not like you will never sell your
house. Eventually, you might sell your
house or you might want to, you know,
mortgage it or do something with it.
There's a lot of things you can do with
it, right? And I think what you want is
you want that hard asset that you can
use when you need to use it. Bitcoin is
just a tool. It's a very good tool, but
you should use it
because it's money. What you should
think about is it's something you can
pass on to future generations that does
not degrade, right? If you buy property,
you know,
you have to repair it, maintain it.
You don't know what's going to happen to
it in 100 years for your your kids, but
Bitcoin is digital. There's no physical
form to it. You know it's still going to
be Bitcoin in 100 years.
>> Okay, all these hardship that we're
enduring to buy Bitcoin, and then what,
right? I think people want to know the
then what.
>> Well, I think that you have to soften it
a bit. So, like I said, never sell your
Bitcoin is a nice thing to say. It's a
slogan.
>> But
a better question is is
what do you want to spend your Bitcoin
on?
>> Right.
>> Now that you have such a valuable asset,
you have to really question
like, what am I really doing with it? Am
I selling it to buy a car?
Do I need the car?
>> Mhm.
>> Or [clears throat] am I selling it to
buy, I don't know,
some plastic thing that's going to melt,
right? Or am I selling it for a life
experience to go somewhere and see
something I really want to see.
So, it's really that you have this
pristine asset
that is generational
and is likely going to appreciate
massively.
It really forces you to think carefully
about what you're going to spend.
>> Mhm.
>> Which is not something that happens
right now. In fact, like I said, people
don't have savings. They're in debt.
Most people are in in in debt in the
world.
Possibly less so in Asia, more in the
US.
But, they're spending
their future money because they want
instant gratification
and instant reward in this fiat world.
And Bitcoin is the exact opposite of
that. And you have to question
what I'm doing today, is it worth it?
And that's only a question you yourself
can answer.
>> You reminded me of something. So, there
are a few times when when I talk about
Bitcoin and I have comments saying that,
"Oh, don't listen to her. She's just
pumping her bag." And I'm just flattered
because if you think I can pump Bitcoin,
I'm like, "Thank you."
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
I I assume people would say the same
thing about you talking about Bitcoin.
>> I haven't heard that, but you know, I'm
sure I haven't I maybe haven't seen it.
But Bitcoin is the only thing where you
it doesn't matter if you pump your bag
or not because it is sort of
preordained where Bitcoin is going. And
Bitcoin is the best
asset too. So, it's like,
do I really need to pump my bag? It kind
of sells itself.
>> Mhm.
>> Whereas everything else, they do need to
pump their bags. They need a marketing
team. Like, this is one of the big
differentiators from uh Bitcoin and
Ethereum. Which was Ethereum's launch
with a 30-person marketing team. I don't
think people know that. But all the If
you go back in time and you look at
their pitch, like the world computer,
it's all slick branding and graphics.
And they like trademark their logo.
It's It's all a very well-packaged thing
to sell to somebody.
But every altcoin is you know, it was
made to be sold to get Bitcoin.
>> But would you say, "Okay." Would you say
these tokens have utility? Or these
chains?
>> No.
>> No?
>> Any utility can be replicated. And you
actually see this. Um like Solana.
You can say it's a better Ethereum. It's
faster, more performant,
newer technology.
>> Would you You it's useful?
>> It's It's useful as a transport layer
for things, but in and of itself, it's
not useful. But, a transport layer could
be anything. Like, it could also be a
centralized database.
And just like, you know, Solana is
better than Ethereum, there will be a
better thing than Solana in the future.
And then, a couple years later, a better
one of that. So, these are not things
you store value in. They're just,
you know,
it's like transient technology.
>> So, they're in different categories.
>> Because they're not money.
>> Mhm.
But, they could be tech stocks.
>> Yeah, kind of. That's a very generous
positive way to frame it, yeah.
>> How would you frame it?
>> I don't know. A copy.
A clone. Temu Bitcoin.
>> Of Bitcoin?
>> Yeah.
>> But, Bitcoin's not trying to do all
that.
>> No, it's not. Like, Bitcoin has second
layer technology that can do all that.
Like,
you know, Taproot assets
can do that transport layer. RGB can do
that. All the Bitcoin related
technologies, Liquid can do that.
>> [snorts]
>> It can all be done without a token. It's
just
people think it you need a token to do
something.
>> I want to go back to the policy.
You mentioned Clarity Act, but I think
it's um
so chaotic, people don't know what's
going on.
Does that have any effect on Bitcoin and
Bitcoin price?
>> People think it does. They think like,
when the Clarity Act passes, then uh
Bitcoin's going to go up.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't really think it has that big of
an impact. It has more to do with
banking and stablecoins than anything
else.
Like, did you stablecoin yield? That's
the sticking point right now.
>> But, I guess everything leads to
Bitcoin. So, if that is good for a
crypto, then it's good for a Bitcoin,
then
>> Not really. I think
uh crypto can go to zero, and Bitcoin
will be fine.
It's a different ball game.
>> But would you want that to happen
because that would be dangerous for
Bitcoin because the public will see that
as oh, cryptocurrency.
>> I mean, cryptocurrency does more damage
to Bitcoin I think than anything else.
Like a lot of these drawdowns that we've
seen are because of things like um
crypto blow-ups like
Terra Luna.
>> Mhm.
>> That had an impact on Bitcoin price.
>> FTX, FTT token as collateral.
Something that came from zero went to
zero.
That impacted Bitcoin massively and it
changed the perception of Bitcoin, too,
cuz I remember we were engaging with
countries and talking about Bitcoin and
then that blew up and then nobody wanted
to talk anymore, right?
>> So, in theory, yes, in practice it's
already bad for Bitcoin, right? Scams,
fraud.
You know, all of it is bad.
Bitcoin has to survive on its own merit
without dependency on any derivative.
>> For a person that's starting today,
let's say he's or she is new to
Bitcoin.
What's the first step?
>> I would say get a little bit of Bitcoin.
Um you can use Aqua.
Um have a friend that has Bitcoin send
you a lightning transaction for, you
know, a couple satoshis.
And just experience it for yourself. I
think that's the biggest thing. People
can't really fathom that
you can just receive money with no
intermediary.
Because you've been born into and grew
up in a world where you have to ask for
permission to use money from somebody.
Counterparty.
Some some group, your bank, Venmo,
PayPal. I don't know what's popular in
Taiwan, but somebody's giving you
permission to transact.
And with Bitcoin it just removes that
barrier.
The better way to think about a Bitcoin
wallet is
it's like a notebook. You You open up
your notebook and someone can write a
number on your notebook and
that's it. It's your notebook.
>> Why are you doing what you do? Because
it's open source, people can download
it.
>> Well,
>> How How do you
Where is the catch? People are like, how
do you make money?
>> Well, Aqua makes money when you do a
swap. If you're swapping from Bitcoin to
um a stable coin or
from uh liquid to lightning.
But, the reason why we're doing this is
because we think onboarding the world to
Bitcoin is
the most important thing right now.
>> I I do think this is a very good time to
learn about Bitcoin, especially when
you're not affected by all these FOMO
and news headlines and stuff.
Um
>> But, with lightning, you can send, you
know, hundreds of satoshis, you know,
couple cents.
And you know, I don't think it's peop-
like if you have a Bitcoin friend,
they'll be happy to send you a few
satoshis. They're not going to send you
one Bitcoin. But, they'll send you a few
satoshis.
>> Anything else you would like to say to
let's say a young viewer just starting
off?
>> Understand what it means to think from
first principles, not just from wealth
creation and money, but for everything
in life.
Because
that is the only way that you can really
achieve success. If you do what everyone
else does, you will be
average.
If you do what the media tells you do or
you
invest based off of some guy
recommending investments,
you're going to end up, you know,
average. You have to think
what is meaningful, what are the things
happening in the world today, and
extrapolate from that for yourself.
And there's no way other way around it.
It's hard work. You have to put in the
work and research, right? Like one thing
I think people should be worrying about,
and maybe they are, is what happens to
your work in the future with AI.
And I think it the answer is Bitcoin,
right? If you have an asset, you can
leverage the asset. You can borrow
against it, right? If there's no more
work, if work becomes a commodity
because uh a computer can do it,
then
what value do you bring? So, you need to
accumulate an asset now, right? If you
go back to the boomer age,
what is the asset? You have the
productive asset of real estate. I can
buy a house, not the one I'm living in,
and I can rent out that house, right?
And I get some income.
Well, with Bitcoin, you can also use it,
too, right? You can borrow against it,
you can sell options, you can do all
sorts of things with it. But
you have to think, if the world is
moving away from work being valuable,
then
there's no more valuable skill than
having an asset. It's not a skill, but
it's like a important thing now. Not
that you know how to do something, but
you have an asset.
>> Talking about this, there's this
narrative that says Bitcoin is not built
for human, it's for AI.
>> I'm pretty sure it's for humans.
>> It's not because, you know, AI agents,
you know, do transactions in very micro
amount and a lot of
>> That doesn't matter. The You can say
Bitcoin's for AIs, but the reason for
that is because it's permissionless.
The AI is not going to get a credit
card, right? The AI is going to use your
credit card. You're going to set up a
credit card account because AIs don't
get credit cards, right? I don't think
they will get credit cards.
Um AIs are not going to have bank
accounts, right? It'll be your bank
account that you delegate access to.
The only thing the AI can really have is
a Bitcoin wallet.
And maybe stablecoins.
>> Mhm.
>> The speed and size of the transaction
doesn't matter. If you could have a
you know
some digital bank account or digital
account, you can have small accounts
just small transactions, too.
But, it's the fact that Bitcoin is
permissionless that
that's what they'll use because that's
the only thing they can use.
>> So, it's just a bonus.
It's not made for AI. It just happens to
be perfect for AI.
>> Yes.
But, you know, everyone has to spin it
somehow with a new narrative. So, they
say, "Oh,
crypto's for AI."
It's just a new new angle that people
are spinning just like the world
computer or something else. But, usually
the reality is simpler than that.
>> I don't know. What's the best way to
describe it? You talk about Bitcoin all
the time.
>> There's no simple
>> It's hard.
>> There's no simple one-shot answer. Like,
I'll give you two statements. Okay.
Bitcoin is digital gold, which means it
is a an asset that doesn't have a
physical form.
The second one I would say is
Bitcoin is information.
Because
it's just information.
Just like
why can I have no counterparty risk?
Because it's just information I send
around the world, right? I don't need a
counterparty to store information.
It's just
ones and zeros.
So, I think there's no one statement
that can encapsulate Bitcoin, but you
can take these two
and you can get pretty far with these
two
in terms of what it means and the impact
on the world.
>> So, if I really want to help you with
this nation-state adoption, what could I
do?
>> I think what you're doing now, just
educate people about Bitcoin and build a
community.
And
if you have connections, engage with
government. We're happy to help, too,
but you can also engage without us.
Like, we go where we're called and
people ask for our help because we're
sort of um
an expert group, right? And we can speak
to our experience. We can speak to what
other countries are doing, but you don't
need us. You can do it fine on your own.
But we're happy to help wherever we can
help.
>> So, does it have to be lawmakers or
companies,
or is it just nations?
>> For us, we're focused on nations, so it
would be lawmakers and politicians.
But companies, too, are good. Like every
segment has a role to play, from the
individual to a company to a country.
>> I [snorts] love what you're doing. Thank
you for being here.
>> Thank you.
>> Bye-bye.